When we want to launch a fleet of devices in the IoT world, we first think of operators and subscriptions.
But in LoRaWAN, things are different because the frequencies use all over the world are free bands.
It means that everyone can use them.
This frequency in Europe is 868 megahertz, but in other region, in the US, for example, it's 915
megahertz.
Or in China it's 470 megahertz and so on.
There are now ten frequency bands that covers almost all the different regions of the world.
So in the Lorawan specification, we have to refer to the document called regional parameters.
If you want to know the frequency band used for a specific region.
So as anyone can use the lorawan bands, they won't be only operators to provide lorawan connectivity.
Actually, there are many different architecture that we're going to see in the next video.
There will be public operators network, private network, hybrid network and finally community network.
All we need to know are the advantages and disadvantages of all these architectures so we can choose
the best solution for our use case.
So let's dive into the details of the first architecture.